<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data platform on Mert Kavi</title>
    <link>https://mertkavi.com/tags/data-platform/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data platform on Mert Kavi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2022 Mert Kavi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 13:15:05 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mertkavi.com/tags/data-platform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building common components in Data Lakehouse is a necessity</title>
      <link>https://mertkavi.com/building-common-components-in-data-lakehouse-is-a-necessity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 13:15:05 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mertkavi.com/building-common-components-in-data-lakehouse-is-a-necessity/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: Any opinions expressed are solely my own. Introduction # In today&amp;rsquo;s world, nearly every product can be considered a data product. However, the ways in which they use data can vary greatly, with some being more data-intensive than others. This presents new challenges for data-reliant systems, such as ensuring data freshness and providing quick responses to queries. Businesses need to be able to gain insights from this data in a timely manner to stay competitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Kubernetes is important for the future of data platforms?</title>
      <link>https://mertkavi.com/why-kubernetes-is-important-for-the-future-of-data-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 13:15:05 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mertkavi.com/why-kubernetes-is-important-for-the-future-of-data-platforms/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: Any opinions expressed are solely my own. Introduction # In brief, Kubernetes is a platform for automating and allocating containers that includes built-in features for healing, scheduling, and deployment practices (such as rollouts and rollbacks), as well as load-balancing and auto-scaling capabilities. Containers are abstracted by the name &amp;ldquo;Pod&amp;rdquo; within Kubernetes.
Kubernetes architecture # Problem # Nowadays, numerous industries face the challenge of collecting and integrating data to solve complex problems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
